Fernanda Hervella

DATA ANALYTICS | DATA SCIENCE | DIGITALIZATION

ABOUT ME

My passion is the development of data projects that have a tangible impact on the ground. I have over six years of experience in managing and developing international digital projects. One of my differentiators is my field experience in various sectors such as Renewable Energies and Food/Beverages. My focus is on simplifying the decision-making process through user empathy and process automation.

EXPERIENCE

GLOBAL HSE DATA ANALYTICS & INTELLIGENCE MANAGER

Siemens Gamesa Renewable Energy Mar. 2021 – Present

LATAM HSE DATA ANALYTICS & INTELLIGENCE MANAGER

Siemens Gamesa Renewable Energy Ago. 2018 – Mar. 2021

ENVIRONMENT, HEALTH, AND SAFETY

PepsiCo

Oct. 2014 - Ago. 2018

EHS CONSULTANCY

Secorh Consultores May. 2012 – Oct. 2014

PROJECTS

ONE-STOP-SHOP | SIEMENS GAMESA RENEWABLE ENERGY

- OSS is a project that allows the company to centralize data, performance indicators, and department reports to ensure transparency and automate the data analysis process.
- This serves all users of the company from the Executive Committee to the front line, consisting of more than 130 tables, over 100 relationships in the model, and over 600 DAX measures that enable the company to make decisions through reliable and accessible data.
- This project has allowed the department for the first time to unify indicators, have real-time data availability, and automate both standardized and usercustomizable reports.

FIVE MINUTES TALK APP | SIEMENS GAMESA RENEWABLE ENERGY

- This application allows the Supervisor to access the 5-minute Talk (a safety process where risks are communicated to the frontline) from their cell phone and collect signatures to generate attendance lists.
- Additionally, the generated data allows the organization to measure the implementation level of this process and cross-reference data between the topics of the talks and the factors contributing to accident generation.

Other Projects: Work Permit App, Wind Turbine Inspection App, Assisted Comments App on Dashboards, Incident Reporting App, and Request Management for the Data Analytics System App.

CONTACT

Fernanda.hervella@hotmail.com (+52) 55 22 60 02 56 <u>LinkedIn</u> Nuevo Leon, Mexico

EDUCATION

Master's in Data Science UNIR 2023 – Present

Advanced Microsoft Power BI LinkedIn Scrum Master LinkedIn Power BI: Integrating AI and Machine Learning LinkedIn Microsoft Power Automate: Business Process Flows LinkedIn Green belt (Internal Certification) Abr. 2021

Universidad Autónoma de Aguascalientes Bachelor's in Industrial Relations Ago. 2014

TECH SKILLS

MS Power BI MS Power Apps MS Power Automate MS SharePoint Dax

LANGUAGE

Spanish – Native English – Proficient